<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome! on Maxi Redigonda&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://mredigonda.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome! on Maxi Redigonda&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 16:46:41 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mredigonda.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2-Minutes Rule</title>
      <link>https://mredigonda.github.io/blog/how-to-complete-the-many-tasks-in-your-backlog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 11:03:01 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mredigonda.github.io/blog/how-to-complete-the-many-tasks-in-your-backlog/</guid>
      <description>We add all tasks that we have to or wish to do to our favorite to do list app. After some time, there are too many of them, and many of them are not even written correctly, or even if they are, they don&amp;rsquo;t get any of our time.
2-Minutes Rule The stuppidest thing I did that incredibly worked out outstandingly well was to force myself to spend 2 minutes on each task, sorted from top to bottom in priority (if any), no skipping at all, every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toolbelt</title>
      <link>https://mredigonda.github.io/toolbelt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 19:36:53 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mredigonda.github.io/toolbelt/</guid>
      <description>This is my hardware and software setup, along with my review of the tools I&amp;rsquo;m currently using.
Hardware Setup  Operating System: Ubuntu 20.04.1 LTS Processor: AMD® Ryzen 3 3200g with Radeon Vega graphics × 4 Motherboard: Gigabyte GA-A320M-S2H Ryzen 2nd Gen Ready M-ATX RAM Memory: Memory ADATA DDR4 16GB 3000MHz XPG Gammix D30 Power Supply Unit: Sentey SDP650-FX 650W Solid Power 80 Plus Case: Aerocool Bolt Black Keyboard: Noga NKB-78011 Mouse: Genius DX-110 Headphones: Audio-Technica ATH-M20x Monitor: LG 24&amp;rdquo; IPS VGA HDMI Full HD FreeSync 24MK430H-B Speakers: Kolke KPC-046 Black  Software Setup  Time Management: Clockify Knowledge Base: Visual Studio Code Code Editor: Visual Studio Code Tasks Management: TickTick Work Communications: Slack Spaced Repetition: Anki Web Browser: Brave Money Management: RealByte&amp;rsquo;s MoneyManager  My Software Review Time Management - Clockify Clockify is an awesome piece of software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brazilian ICPC Summer School 2018</title>
      <link>https://mredigonda.github.io/blog/brazilian-icpc-summer-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mredigonda.github.io/blog/brazilian-icpc-summer-school/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a two weeks long event, with theoretic lectures from outstanding instructors in the mornings, and competitive programming contests in the afternoons. It was held from January 22nd to February 3rd in the city of Campinas, São Paulo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>