<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome! on Maxi Redigonda&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://mredigonda.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome! on Maxi Redigonda&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 16:46:41 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mredigonda.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Toolbelt</title>
      <link>https://mredigonda.github.io/toolbelt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 19:36:53 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mredigonda.github.io/toolbelt/</guid>
      <description>This is my hardware and software setup, along with my review of the tools I&amp;rsquo;m currently using.
Hardware Setup  Operating System: Ubuntu 18.04.4 LTS Processor: AMD® Ryzen 3 2200g with Radeon Vega graphics × 4 Motherboard: Gigabyte GA-A320M-S2H Ryzen 2nd Gen Ready M-ATX RAM Memory: Memory ADATA DDR4 16GB 3000MHz XPG Gammix D30 Power Supply Unit: Sentey SDP650-FX 650W Solid Power 80 Plus Case: GameMax Centauri H601BR Black Keyboard: Noga NKB-78011 Mouse: Scorpion Marvo M221 Headphones: Audio-Technica ATH-M20x Monitor: LG 24&amp;rdquo; IPS VGA HDMI Full HD FreeSync 24MK430H-B Speakers: Kolke KPC-046 Black  Software Setup  Time Management: Clockify Knowledge Base: Visual Studio Code Code Editor: Visual Studio Code Tasks Management: TickTick Work Communications: Slack Spaced Repetition: Anki Web Browser: Brave Money Management: RealByte&amp;rsquo;s MoneyManager  My Software Review Time Management - Clockify Clockify is an awesome piece of software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brazilian ICPC Summer School 2018</title>
      <link>https://mredigonda.github.io/blog/brazilian-icpc-summer-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mredigonda.github.io/blog/brazilian-icpc-summer-school/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a two weeks long event, with theoretic lectures from outstanding instructors in the mornings, and competitive programming contests in the afternoons. It was held from January 22nd to February 3rd in the city of Campinas, São Paulo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>