<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Maxi Redigonda&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://mredigonda.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Maxi Redigonda&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 08:49:40 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mredigonda.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Will everything be faster when Moore&#39;s law is over?</title>
      <link>https://mredigonda.github.io/blog/will-everything-be-faster-when-moores-law-is-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 08:49:40 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mredigonda.github.io/blog/will-everything-be-faster-when-moores-law-is-over/</guid>
      <description>Moore&amp;rsquo;s law is not really a law, it&amp;rsquo;s just the observation that the number of transistors in computers doubles every two years.
The power of computers has been increasing exponentially for a long time, but we know that due to physical constraints, there&amp;rsquo;s a limit to how much it can grow, at least in the traditional way of adding more transistors*.
Another law, the Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s law, is an adage that says: &amp;ldquo;work expands so as to fill the time available for its completion&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Tips</title>
      <link>https://mredigonda.github.io/blog/ubuntu-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 19:44:33 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mredigonda.github.io/blog/ubuntu-tips/</guid>
      <description>Disable animations, it makes the experience much much faster.
Once you disable animations, using the apps grid (shortcut SUPER + A by default) is lighting fast, and works as an application launcher (it covers the most basic functionality of applications like ulauncher).
Finally, try to set up a script to install your common programs, and also track every configuration change that you do. A git repo with a markdown file will do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2-Minutes Rule</title>
      <link>https://mredigonda.github.io/blog/how-to-complete-the-many-tasks-in-your-backlog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 11:03:01 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mredigonda.github.io/blog/how-to-complete-the-many-tasks-in-your-backlog/</guid>
      <description>We add all tasks that we have to or wish to do to our favorite to do list app. After some time, there are too many of them, and many of them are not even written correctly, or even if they are, they don&amp;rsquo;t get any of our time.
2-Minutes Rule The stuppidest thing I did that incredibly worked out outstandingly well was to force myself to spend 2 minutes on each task, sorted from top to bottom in priority (if any), no skipping at all, every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brazilian ICPC Summer School 2018</title>
      <link>https://mredigonda.github.io/blog/brazilian-icpc-summer-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mredigonda.github.io/blog/brazilian-icpc-summer-school/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a two weeks long event, with theoretic lectures from outstanding instructors in the mornings, and competitive programming contests in the afternoons. It was held from January 22nd to February 3rd in the city of Campinas, São Paulo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>